let's look at the solution to our block
size quiz we have a 32 kilobyte cache
with 64 byte block size and the program
that accesses n variables that have lots
of temporal locality meaning each of
these variables is accessed often in the
program but no spatial locality meaning
they are nowhere close to each other the
question is what is the largest n the
number of these variables that still
results in a high hit rate now x1 when
we bring it into the cache we will bring
an entire block worth of stuff around it
and because there is no spatial locality
that means that none of the other
variables will be in that block when we
access x2 same thing we will bring 64
bytes worth of stuff that doesn't
include any of the other variables so
every time we access one of these
variables we will need 64 bytes worth of
space in the cache if we want to have a
high hit rate because these variables
have lots of temporal locality we want
all of them to remain in the cache that
is we want all of them to fit in the
cache so the largest n that still
results in the high hit rate is how many
blocks can we fit in your cache really
it's a 32 kilobyte cache there are 64
byte blocks how many blocks do we have
so the answer is 32 kilobytes divided by
64 bytes which gives us 512 so the
answer here is 512 if we have 512 or
fewer variables then the fact that each
one of them has its own cache block in
the cache although of the variables
probably only 4 bytes in size is not
gonna hurt us in terms of hit rate but
if we have more than 512 variables then
even though there is plenty of space in
the cache if it's 4 byte variables 512
variables is 2 kilobytes worth of actual
stuff that we are using the block is
much larger than that but because we are
fetching an entire block when we have a
Miss we will not have a good hit rate if
you have
more than 512 of these variables in
order to be able to have more variables
than this we really need them to be
close to each other so that we can
benefit from spatial locality meaning
that a block we fetch for one variable
needs to include some of the other
variables